cicnews.com 2019-04-23

# CIC News - Privacy Policy

## ABOUT CIC NEWS

The domain name [**www.CICNews.com**](https://www.cicnews.com/) is part of the **Campbell Cohen Immigration Network** ( _henceforth referred to as the CCIN or “our” or “we”_ ), which is a division of the Campbell Cohen Law Firm. This Privacy Policy applies to the operations of all network properties and services within the _CCIN_ family of websites, unless specifically indicated otherwise. The _CCIN_ is a collection of Canadian Immigration related web properties which offer various customized and value-added services that facilitate the process of immigration to Canada.

**The _CCIN_ includes the following websites: **  
[CanadaVisa.com](https://www.canadavisa.com/), [CICNews.com](https://www.cicnews.com/), and [CanadaStudyNews.com.](https://www.canadastudynews.com/)

**Our postal address is:**  
1303 Greene Ave., Suite 200  
Westmount, Montreal, QC, Canada  
H3Z 2A7  
1.514.937.9445  
1.888.947.9445 (Toll free in North America)

This Privacy Policy outlines our commitment to the privacy of all visitors to the _CCIN_ , and fully describes when, why and how we collect personal data in a secure manner. Your use of _CCIN_ Internet sites and services is subject to the following Privacy Policy. In addition, your use of our sites and associated services constitutes your acceptance of these terms.

**COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA**

_Contact Data_

  * You have the option of submitting personal contact data in the course of accessing our sites. These contact details are stored in a secure data centre within North America so that we may respond to any requests made by you. Visitors who supply us with their telephone number(s) and email address(es) online will only receive contact from us regarding matters relating to Canadian immigration and/or settlement in Canada and/or studying in Canada.

_Personal Data_

  * For each visitor to our websites, our server automatically captures anonymous data like your IP address, but does not capture personally identifiable data like your email address.
  * You may be asked to provide personal information in certain fields on our websites. This personal information will not be disclosed, leased or transferred without your consent, and will be used solely for the purposes for which it was requested.
  * The personal data you provide to us in the [_Eligibility Questionnaire_](https://www.canadavisa.com/assess/canada-immigration-assessment-form.htm) is collected for the purpose of assessing your potential to immigrate to Canada under Canada’s current immigration selection criteria. Any personal information submitted to us will not be sold, or otherwise transferred, to a third-party source without your consent. Upon submitting your _Canada Immigration Eligibility Questionnaire_ , you can expect your results to be delivered to the email address you have provided to us within 24 hours from the time of submission. Thereafter, we may send follow-up emails to the same email address regarding your Canadian immigration inquiry, unless you have unsubscribed or requested to no longer receive these emails.
  * If you choose to submit your resume to us, it will be used to evaluate your eligibility for Canadian immigration. Resumes are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with any entity unrelated to the _CCIN_ without your consent

_Data Security_

  * We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving sensitive client data exchanged with our sites.
  * All of the information that we collect from you, such as registration and assessment details, or any other personally identifiable information, is stored in a secure data centre within North America.

_Website Cookies_

  * Cookies are small files that are placed onto your device when you visit online properties. The files help analyze website traffic and page visits in order to tailor online services to your individual preferences.
  * When you visit the _CCIN_ , we may assign your device one or more cookies to facilitate access to our sites and to personalize your online experience. Through the use of these cookies, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on our sites, such as the pages you visit, the time and date of your visits, the links you click, and the searches you conduct. While the information collected cannot be used to identify you, cookies provide important data for our marketing department. During your visits to other websites, we (or third parties) may use certain anonymous, non-personal data collected on the _CCIN_ to show you advertisements likely to be of greater interest to you.
  * We may allow third parties, including authorized service providers and advertising companies like Facebook and Google, to employ third-party cookies to collect anonymous information. Our websites do not provide any personal information to these third parties without your consent. These third parties may collect information about your browsing habits, such as pages visited, links followed, and external websites visited. This information may allow them to deliver more relevant advertisements, to limit the number of times you see advertisements, and to gauge campaign effectiveness.
  * Most browsers have cookies enabled by default, but you can usually modify your browser settings to disable cookies. If you choose to disable cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in or use some of the interactive features offered on our websites.
  * The option to change cookies settings is typically found in the ‘Options’ or ‘Preferences’ menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful. Otherwise, you should use the ‘Help’ option in your browser for more details. 
    * Cookie settings in [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-ca/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)
    * Cookie settings in [Firefox](http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Cookies)
    * Cookie settings in [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en)
    * Cookie settings in [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_CA) web and [iOS](https://support.apple.com/en-ca/HT201265)

_Online Behavioural Advertising (OBA)_

  * During your visits to other websites, we (or third parties like Facebook and Google) may use certain anonymous, non-personal data collected on our sites to show you advertisements likely to be of greater interest to you, which is called Online Behavioural Advertising (OBA).
  * None of the OBA techniques we use will collect information such as your name, email address, postal address or phone number.
  * Our partners or third parties may use OBA to show you advertisements based on your behaviour. If you want to opt out of receiving online behavioural advertising, please visit [http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN) or <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>. The opt-out function does not mean that you will no longer receive advertising when visiting sites, but that the advertising you see will not be customized based on your behaviour.

_The Canada Immigration Newsletter_

  * The _Canada Immigration Newsletter_ is a web-based publication edited by Canadian Immigration Attorney David Cohen. The newsletter is distributed electronically and delivered directly to your inbox at least twice per month. It may also be accessed directly on [CICNews.com](https://www.cicnews.com/). When you opt to receive the _Canada Immigration Newsletter_ , you are consenting to the delivery of email messages concerning topics related to Canadian immigration. Your email address, as well as any personal information you provide to us, will not be disclosed to any third-party websites without your consent and will be used solely for the purposes for which it was requested.
  * If you wish to opt-out of any future delivery of the Canada Immigration Newsletter, simply click on the ‘Unsubscribe’ link located at the bottom of every newsletter we send you. Alternatively, you can visit our [unsubscribe page](https://www.cicnews.com/unsubscribe.html) to remove your name from our newsletter delivery database.

_External Hyperlinks_

  * Our sites may provide hyperlinks to other locations or websites on the Internet outside the _CCIN_ group. These hyperlinks lead to websites published or operated by third parties who are not affiliated with or in any way related to the _CCIN_ entity. They have been included in our website to enhance your user experience and are presented for information purposes only. We endeavor to select reputable websites and sources of information for your convenience. We are not in any way responsible for the content of any externally linked website or webpage. You may use or follow these links at your own risk and we are not responsible for any damages or losses arising out of or in connection with your use of the links.

**ACCESS TO PERSONAL DATA**

_Contact Us_

  * You have the right to view, amend or delete the personal information that we hold about you. If you have any questions or concerns regarding your privacy or this Privacy Policy, you may [contact us](https://www.canadavisa.com/contact-us.html).
